TAEK BEEN NAM

Grand Rapids, MI, US | +1 (616) 254-7534 | taekbeen93@gmail.com github.com/tnamdevnote | linkedin.com/in/taekbeen-nam/

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Frontend Engineer with 3+ years of professional experience. Enjoy creating polished, visually coherent, user interfaces, but also passionate about crafting products that enhance user experience. Genuinely curious about things that influence human behaviors. Self Driven, quick learner, and always looking for opportunities for growth.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Frontend Engineer, Eidex

MAR 2022 - AUG 2023

- Designed and developed 5+ UI components, including dropdown, cards, and popover menu, using React, styled-components, and and to enhance customizability while maintaining consistency in overall design of the applications.
- Refactored legacy dashboard UI to migrate away from outdated libraries and to modernize codebase to follow the team's new development practices; replaced 2 third-party libraries with in-house solutions using vanilla CSS and browser API, while preserving core features of the dashboard.
- Redesigned and implemented the user interface of 4+ major features as part of the product renewal project (PRISM 2.0).
- Configured the initial settings of theme, such as color scheme and typography, using styled components and MUIThemeProvider, providing a structured way for peer developers to apply styles to their work while adhering to the given style guides.
- Took the initiative for filling in the UI/UX designer role by creating wireframes and interactive prototypes using Figma
 for more than 5 legacy feature updates in order to facilitate communication between the client service team and the
 development team.

Junior Frontend Engineer, Eidex

DEC 2019 - MAR 2022

- Used React daily to create and maintained 128+ visualizations of school data that help educators analyze trends to improve and support student success
- Built UI for a file sharing system using React and Redux, allowing educators to be notified with up-to-date school reports as well as have access to more than 1000+ school reports at any time.
- Organized a meeting with the product owner and senior engineers at the beginning of each sprint to collect business requirements and report current progress

Data Warehouse Specialist, Eidex

NOV 2018 - DEC 2019

- Developed data pipelines using SQL to ingest statewide assessment data, creating data views for utilization in BI tools like Qliksense
- Gathered and analyzed business requirements and transformed data accordingly
- Maintained weekly data load in order for clients' to have access to up-to-date data in all the product (PRISM 1.0 and Focus 3.0)

QA Analyst, Eidex

NOV 2016 - NOV 2018

- Learned SQL and basic RDBMS concepts within a month; Expedited data validation process by 50% by writing reusable test queries using SQL after two months
- Documented testing manual for the product data validation process, which was adopted across the development team
- Conducted market research on the 7 new statewide assessment and its education system to provide strategic insights to the client service team; documented wiki pages for 7 new statewide assessments

SKILLS

Languages: TypeScript, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, SQL

Technologies: React, redux, redux-saga, styled components, MUI, Figma, Framer Motion, Git, Github, Snowflake, Qliksense

EDUCATION

Full stack Software Engineering Track, Springboard Bootcamp

FEB 2021- DEC 2021

- Completed 50% of the coursework
- Completed course on Web Fundamentals, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Redux, and Capstone Project

B.A., Sociology, Calvin University GPA (3.7/4.0)

MAY 2016

PROJECTS

Build Youtube (https://github.com/tnamdevnote/youtube-clone/)

JAN 2023 - MAR 2023

- Built client-side Youtube application in order to learn and apply frontend development practices, including theming, routing, and data fetching. The application provides search and streaming features using Youtube Data API.
- Utilize dependency injection pattern, and React Context to decouple API layer from the application, making it easier to maintain even if Youtube DATA API is changed.
- Customized themes using TailwindCSS to ensure consistent look and feel of the UI.